Hello programmer, welcome back to our SQL T2 series.
So today I am going to explore the group by
clause in the SQL. And first of all, I can simply just
define the create for the SQL group by clause. So
group by clause in the SQL is to
group raw that have the same value into the summary row.
And it is incredibly useful for performing the aggregate function
in the group by data, okay? So first of all, here I'll use the grouping data by a
single column, okay? And first of all, here
I can just type this is select and use the address, okay?
So define for the address column, and now just here type for the
average salary, okay? So define for the average
salary as used for the AVG underscore, this is the salary column.
And now just go for another line where I can just type the prompt.
This is the customer stable, okay?
So this is the customer stable and use here this is a
group by clause and here I can just define again this is the address.
So it will be our address address column, okay? So now here simply just
create and first of all, here I can select
and then execute now, okay? So just execute, you can see here perfectly
see the today first use the print for address and
average salary, okay? So you can see here perfectly understand
this output section, okay? So I hope you perfectly understand
this is the complete output show for the display, okay?
So here completely create the single column, okay?
And next step here, create this is a use for the group by clause in the
multiple columns, okay? So here I can use for the example just
grouping the customer table based on the customer address and the age, okay?
So first of all, here I define for what address and also here declare for the
age column, okay? So now here use the sum function
and then use the salary as a total salary, okay?
So now here perfectly define the total salary from the customer table
is grouped by the average and the age column, okay?
So now completely create in this data query now
I can just select all in this data query and then execute now, okay?
You can see here perfectly see the output
so first print at this column, next print for the age column, okay?
And lastly here, print the total salary, so you can see here the perfectly
the total salary of the average and the age column, okay?
So I hope you perfectly understand this example.
So next step here just use another example just finding out
highest salary for each age column, okay? So here I'm going to
use this age address column only use for the
age column and you can just type this is the maximum salary
as here just change this completely just type here the maximum salary
from the customer's table, use the group by
only the age, okay? So here perfectly create and now
select all and then execute and you can see here perfectly
created the age is 22 and the maximum salary is
45 hundred, okay? And here in this line the maximum salary
for the 24 age and here the 10,000, okay?
So I hope you understand completely done for in this example
and here also is for another example. So here I'll use the
group by only order function, okay? So here is the example
find the highest salary for the age sorted by the
high or the low, okay? So here I use for the maximum
and change for here the minimum function for the
minimum salary, okay? So I'll define the minimum salary
and going for here the customer table, okay?
Then the next step here I'm going to use the group by
for the age and here I can also use the order
by calls for the minimum underscore
this salary and it will look at completely
descending order, okay? So now here just type
the output for the SQL. So first of all select in this
data query and now just execute and you can see here the results. So
first of all the age and the minimum salary and they are
cleared for sorted by high to low, okay? So high salary
between 1000 and the low for here the total
combined for 80, 500 and the 2500 to 150 and
1500 the minimum salary, okay? So I hope you understand and
here I'll completely just overview the group by clause in
the SQL with some practical example, okay? So I hope you
perfectly understand this session. So now thank you for
Thanks for watching and happy coding, okay?